Indiana History mss., 1725-1973 LMC 1544 LMC 1544
Lilly Library
- Indiana History
  - Methodist Episcopal Church. Conferences. Indiana. Minutes of the Indiana conference of the Methodist Episcopal Church., 1844, Sept. 25-1851, Oct. 15 -; Typed copy. [4], 227 [i.e. 242] p. 23 cm. (Bound 17)
    Transcribed from the original in the office of the Archives, DePauw University, Greencastle, Indiana. 1953
  - Shuck, Daniel, clergyman. Memorandum book, 1844-1854, Oct. 16 -; Autograph Document Signed 46 p. 19 1/2 cm. (Box 1)
    Memorandum book containing report on ministerial activities in the United Brethren in Christ, 1844-1849
    Lists of members of various churches of his denomination, 1847
    Subscribers for a parsonage and support for the church in New Albany, Ind., 1850-1851
    Diary, Jan. 20-Feb. 17, 1851, of activities in Indiana and Ohio
    and Personal finances, 1853-1854.
    Purchase. 1961
  - Methodist Episcopal Church. Conferences. North Indiana. [Minutes of the North Indiana conference of the Methodist Episcopal Church.], 1844, Oct. 16-1851, Aug. 27 -; Typed copy 232 [i.e. 238] p. 23 cm.; copy. (Bound 18)
    Purchase. 1953
  - Long, Avery. Three tax receipts to Greenburg Robertson., 1844, Dec. 16-1846, Dec. 17 -; Autograph Document Signed 3 p. 5 and 6 cm. (Box 1)
  - Indiana. State Bank. Terre Haute Branch. To Bethuel F. Morris, cashier, Indianapolis, Indiana. Report on condition of the branch at Terre Haute of the State Bank of Indiana., 1844, Dec. 31 -; Document Signed 1 p. 28 cm. (Box 1)
    Signed: Nathaniel Preston, cashier.
    Gift. 1948
  - [Plat map of Madison, Ind.]., 1844? -; Autograph Document 1 map.; folio.; 43 x 59 cm. (Box 5)
    Names of residents of Madison ([e.g.] D. Blackmore, J. R. Cravens, W. Hendricks, Jr., D. Hillis, J. F. Lanier, J. Paul, J. P. Paul, on map and D. C. Branham, Robert Branham, W. H. Branham, Elias Stapp on verso) indicate that this is a map of Madison, Ind.
    Plat of lands of D. C., W. H., and Robert Branham on verso with record of size and value of holdings of D. C. and W. H. Branham, dated 1844. Found in the Indiana University copy of the Madison Courier, Madison, Ind., 1848-1849
    Purchase. 1940-1941
  - Polk, James Knox, 1795-1849, pres. U.S. Washington D.C. Grant of land in district of lands subject to sale at Jeffersonville, Ind., to Alvin Wheeler of Jackson County, Ind., 1845, June 1 -; Document 1 p.; folio.; 26 x 37 cm. (Box 5)
    Signature reads: "James K. Polk By J. Knox Walker Sec'y."
    Countersigned: S. H. Laughlin, recorder of the General land office.
    Purchase. 1933
  - Leatherwood Mills, Parke County, Indiana. Account book of operations of linseed oil mill, 1845-1850, and of woolen mill, 1849-1856., 1845-1856 -; Autograph Document 44, [63] p. 31 cm. (Box 1)
    Various pages lacking.
    Mill appears to have been operated by Mahlon Reynolds and Jesse Kemp.
    pp. 1-27; 43-44: Accounts of Siler, & Kemp, James Siler & co., and Kemp and Doggett, merchants, 1837-1838.
    Accompanied by directions for dyeing wool and woolen cloth.
    (Autograph Document 50 p. 31 cm.)
    Gift. 1956
    2 mss.
  - Indiana infantry. 3rd regt., 1846. Co. A. Record of service of C.A., 3rd regt., Indiana volunteers, under the command of Capt. John M. Sluss., 1846, June 6-1847, June 4 -; Document 66 p. 39 cm. (Bound 19)
    This company was raised in Monroe County, Ind.
    Three bills for clothing for members of the company are in pocket on back cover.
  - Indiana infantry. 2nd regt., 1846-1847. Co. F. Muster roll of Captain Henry Davis' company in the 2nd regiment (--- brigade) of Indiana foot volunteers, commanded by Lt. Colonel William R. Haddon called into the service of the United States by the President under the act of Congress approved, May 13, 1846, from the twentieth day of June 1846, when mustered to the 1st day of September 1846., 1846, June 20 -; Document Signed 2 p. 52 cm.; folio. (Box 5)
    Partly printed.
  - Indiana infantry. 2nd regt., 1846-1847. Co. F. Muster roll of Captain Henry Davis' company in the 2nd regiment (--- brigade) of Indiana foot volunteers, commanded by Colonel Joseph Lane, called into the service of the United States by the President under the act of Congress approved, May 13, 1846, from the twentieth day of June 1846, (date of this muster) for the term of twelve months, unless sooner discharged., 1846, June 20 -; Document Signed 2 p. 55 cm.; folio. (Box 5)
  - Indiana infantry. 3rd regt., 1846. Co. A. Muster roll of Captain John M. Sluss company in the 3rd regiment (---brigade) of Indiana foot volunteers, commanded by Colonel James Henry Lane, called into the service of the United States by the President under the act of Congress approved May 13, 1846, from the 22nd day of June 1846 (date of this muster) for the term of twelve months, unless sooner discharged., 1846, June 22 -; Document Signed 2 p. 51 cm.; folio. (Box 5)
    Deposited in the Indiana University Library by George D. Baker and Hays H. Buskirk. Bloomington, Indiana. Letter of deposit and three photostatic copies of the Muster roll included in folder. 1948
  - Indiana infantry. 2nd regt., 1846-1847. Co. F. Muster roll of Captain Henry Davis' company in the 2nd regiment (---brigade) of Indiana volunteers, commanded by Colonel William A. Bowles, called into the service of the United States by the President under the act of Congress approved May 13, 1846 from the first day of September 1846, when last mustered, to the thirty-first day of Oct. 1846., 1846, Sept. 1 -; Document Signed 2 p. 52 cm.; folio. (Box 5)
  - Indiana infantry. 2nd regt., 1846-1847. Co. F. Muster roll of Captain Henry Davis' company in the second regiment (---brigade) of Indiana volunteers, commanded by Colonel William A. Bowles, called into the service of the United States by the President under the act of Congress approved May 13, 1846, from the 31st day of October, 1846, when last mustered to the thirty-first day of December, 1846., 1846, Oct. 31 -; Document Signed 2 p. 52 cm.; folio. (Box 5)
  - Downey, Robert. Deed of land in Mechanic's Retreat, Floyd County, Indiana, by Robert Downey and Barbara Downey to John Yeager., 1846, Dec. 4 -; Document Signed 1 p. 42 cm.; folio. (Box 5)
    Attested by Henry Collins, recorder of the city of New Albany, Indiana.
    Gift. Source unknown. 1946
  - Indiana infantry. 2nd regt., 1846-1847. Co. F. A list of Officers and Privates, "Lawrence Greys.", Autograph Document 8 p. 32 cm. (Box 1)
    This company was raised in Lawrence County, Indiana.
  - Stapp, Milton, 1792-1869, lawyer, lieut.-governor of Indiana. The memoirs of Milton Stapp., 1847, July 14-1864, Sept. 8 -; Typed 110 p. 28 cm.; copy. (Bound 20)
    Copied by Elfrieda Lang from the typescript copy of William S. Dow, December 9, 1953.
    Original in the possession of Dr. C. E. Colgate, a great great grandson of Milton Stapp.
    Copy 1 bound; Copy 2 unbound.
    1953
  - Stapp, Milton, 1792-1869, lawyer, lieut.-governor of Indiana. Unbound manuscript of the memoirs of Milton Stapp, 14 July 1847-8 Sept 1864 (Box 1)
  - Bailey, Thomas, musician,; Co. C., 5th regt., Indiana volunteers. Diary of the Mexican war., 1847, Oct. 30-1848, July 27 -; Document 43 p. 21 cm.; copy. (Box 1)
    Printed in Indiana Magazine of History. 14:134-147, June 1918.
  - Gorman, Willis Arnold, 1816-1876, congressman, general, territorial governor of Minnesota. Puebla, Mexico. To John S. Watts, Bloomington, Ind. Hopes to return home as soon as "it is beyond doubt that a treaty has been concluded and that all it now wants is the sanction of the Congress;" 4th Indiana regiment has seen more service than any troops now in the service, except the old regulars and have proved themselves "worthy representatives of the honor and chivalry of Indiana.", 1848, Feb. 19 -; Autograph Letter Signed 1 p. 33 cm. (Box 1)
  - Polk, James Knox, 1795-1849, pres. U.S. Washington, D.C. Grant of land in the district of lands subject to sale at Jeffersonville, Indiana, to Caleb Crayden, of Harrison County, Indiana., 1848, Apr. 10 -; Document 1 p.; folio.; 24 x 39 cm. (Box 5)
    Signature reads "James Knox Polk. By J. K. Stephens Asst Sec'y."
    Countersigned by S. H. Laughlin, recorder of the General land office.
  - Polk, James Knox, 1795-1849, pres. U.S. Washington, D.C. Grant of land in the district of lands subject to sale at Jeffersonville, Indiana, to Silas Crayden, of Harrison County, Indiana., 1848, Apr. 10 -; Document 1 p.; folio.; 25 x 39 cm. (Box 5)
    Countersigned by S. H. Laughlin, recorder, General land office.
  - Bryan, A. M. Marriage certificate of John W. Conway and Alzora Hill of Vernon, Indiana., 1848, Apr. 14 -; Document Signed 1 p. 14 cm. (Box 1)
  - Simmers, Jacob. Deed of land in Mechanic's Retreat, Floyd County, Indiana, by Jacob Simmers, Jane Simmers, Orange A. Graves and Ellen Graves to John Yeager., 1848, May 31 -; Document Signed 2 p. 25 cm. (Box 1)
    Attested by Henry Collins, city judge, Albany, Ind.
    Gift. 1942
  - Episcopal Bishops of Indiana. Letters written by 11 bishops of Indiana., 1849-1865; 14 letters. Varying sizes. (Box 1)
    Purchase. 2004.
  - Polk, James Knox, 1795-1849, pres. U.S. Washington, D.C. Grant of land in district of lands subject to sale at Jeffersonville, Ind., to Ira Cornett, of Jackson County, Ind., 1849, Feb. 1 -; Document 1 p.; folio.; 25 x 29 cm. (Box 5)
    Signature reads: "James K. Polk by J. K. Stephens Ass't Sec'y."
  - Marion County, Indianapolis and Bellefontaine Railroad Company land indenture, 1 Oct. 1849 (Box 1)
  - Indiana. State Bank. New Albany branch. To Branch bank, Indianapolis, Ind. State of the branch at New Albany of the State Bank of Indiana., 1850, Feb. 28 -; Document Signed 1 p. 40 cm.; folio. (Box 1)
    Signed: V. A. Pepin, cashier.
  - Simmers, Jacob. Deed of land in Mechanic's Retreat, Floyd County, Indiana, by Jacob Simmers and Jane Simmers to John Yeager., 1850, May 24 -; Document Signed 1 p. 41 cm.; folio. (Box 5)
    Attested by Jared C. Jocelyn, J. P., New Albany, Ind.
  - Cravens, Samuel R., Clerk, Green County, Ind. Circuit Court. Marriage license of William B. Tuell and Catharine Marion Topping., 1850, Aug. 14 -; Document Signed 1 p.; 9 x 21 cm. (Box 1)
  - Smith, J. R., Decatur, Adams Co., Indiana. To Lewis B. Kingsbury, Milnersville, Guernsey Co., Ohio., 1850, Aug. 23 -; Autograph Letter Signed 4 pp. 31.5 cm. (Box 1)
    Addressing his "Dear brother & sister," Smith relates the death of the Kingsburys' son John from measles and says that if the "doctor had understood what he ought that he would have remained with us." Expresses concern for the welfare of John's wife and children, but expects Jesse E. Read to look after them. "your Ever affectionate Brother & Sister until death J. R. & Lydia Smith."
    Gift. 1985
  - Rose, Chauncey, 1794-1877, railroad builder, financier, Terre Haute, Ind. To Charles R. Peddle, Indianapolis, Ind., and Erastus Corning, Albany, N.Y. Deals with the shipment of engines for Terre Haute and Richmond Railroad Company from Boston, Mass., to Terre Haute, Ind., 1851, Mar. 14-June 7 -; Typed Letter, 10 items, 16 p. 28 cm.; copies. (Box 1)
    Transcript made from the originals by the owner, Juliet Peddle, Terre Haute, Ind. 1952
  - Indiana. State Bank. Madison branch. Minutes of meetings of Board of directors., 1851, Nov. 3-1904, July -; Document 12 p. 28 cm. (Box 2)
    Gift. 1919
  - Chicago, Indianapolis and Louisville Railway Company. Certificate of stock of the New Albany and Salem Railroad Co., dated Dec. 26, 1853, and issued to William Wylie., 1851, Dec. 29-1853, Dec. 26 -; Document Signed 1 p.; 13 x 23 cm. (Box 2)
    Signed by James Brooks, president, and William W. Tuttle, asst. secretary.
    Includes also: Receipt to William Wylie, dated Bloomington, Dec. 29, 1851, for payment for above stock, signed: Thomas Carter, Collector.
  - Earl, Robert, of Tippecanoe County, Ind. Time book of his employees and account book., 1853, Mar. 7-1879, Feb. 10 -; Document Signed, 5 items, 108 p. 30 cm. (Box 2)
    Four miscellaneous documents in pocket on back cover, Aug. 10, 1873-May 30, 1891.
  - Campbell, Matthew Monroe, 1810-1897, professor, Indiana University. Bloomington, Ind. To Theophilus Adam Wylie, Oxford, Ohio. Concerns the supreme court decision affecting Indiana University and other university news., 1853, Mar. 9 -; Autograph Letter Signed 2 p. 24 cm. (Box 2)
    Gift. 1961
  - Brooks, Lewis, 1835-, trader, army officer. A Journal of a Flatboat trip from Mt. Pleasant, Indiana to New Orleans, Louisiana; and A Journal of a Flat Boat Trip from Mt. Pleasant, Indiana to New Orleans, Louisiana taken from the Journal of the Flat Boat "Snaketown" by Lewis Brooks., 1853, Mar. 15-June 1; 1854, Apr. 4-May 23 -; Typed Document 12 leaves. 33 cm.; copy. (Box 2)
    Corrections and additions in pencil.
    1 item.
  - Morrison, Ellen J., Clayton, Ind. To her sisters. Gives family news., 1853, Dec. 25 -; Autograph Letter Signed 4 p. 25 cm. (Box 2)
  - [Documents related to the legal career of Oliver Perry Morton in Wayne County, Indiana.], 1853-1856 -; Autograph Documents Signed, 12 items, 28 pp. 13-31 cm. (Box 2)
    1) 1853, Sept. 4 – Hannah Hawkins vs. Jeremiah W. Swafford, Complaint to set aside sale; signed by Jacob Burnet Julian and Oliver Perry Morton; Andrew F. Scott, clerk.
    2) 1853, Sept. 17 – Richard Barnard vs. Sanford Lackey, Complaint for judgment of $500; Morton and John F. Kibbey, attys; Scott, clerk.
    3) 1854, Jan. 26 – Thomas Kearns vs. John W. Williamson & William Gillam, Notice of motion to correct decree of foreclosure; Morton & Kibbey, solicitors; Scott, clerk.
    4) 1854, Jan. 26 – Thomas Kearns vs. John W. Williamson & William Gillium, Certified copy by Scott of notice of motion to correct decree of foreclosure, 27 Jan 1854.
    5) 1854, Feb. 16 – Josiah W. Glidden, Ex…of John Weaver vs. Lewis B. Morrison, Replication; Develin & Morton, attys; Scott clerk.
    6-8) 1855, Jan. 25 – Oliver P. Morton and William Baker vs. Alfred Lashley, Appeal bonds (3) for the sums of $45, of $59, of $110; William F. King, Clerk.
    9) 1855, Feb. 2 – Isaac Burbank vs. William F. King et al., complaint to foreclose; Morton & [Telley? or Tilley?], attys; Scott, clerk.
    10) 1856, Jan. 3 – Levi L. Lawrence and James W. Lawrence vs. Norton Davis, et. al., Complaint on note; Morton & Kibbey, attys; Scott, clerk
    11) n.d. – Sarah Kittel[?] vs. John Binkley, Breach of promise suit; Develin & Morton attys
    12) n.d. – David Smith vs. Jeremiah Smith, Exception to the deposition regarding questioning; with signed note in Morton's hand that "the question is leading in its character."
    Formerly in the library of King V. Hostick, Springfield, Illinois.
  - Dearborn County circuit court, U.S. naturalization of German emigrate, 4 Apr. 1854 (Box 2)
  - Union County, Liberty, Indiana; declaration of the intention of Michael Seanleu of Ireland to become a U.S. citizen, 2 Oct. 1854 (Box 2)
  - Warren County, Indiana circuit court; U.S. naturalization of English emigrate, 2 Apr. 1855 (Box 2)
  - German Benevolent and Literary Society, Cannelton, Ind. Articles of association of the German Benevolent and Literary Society (Deutscher Unterstutzungs & Bildungsvererin), 1855, Apr. 3 -; Autograph Document Signed 1 p. 25 cm. (Box 2)
    Date is that of filing.
  - Hunter, David Eckely, 1834-1892, teacher. Diary., 1855, Nov. 9-1857, Feb. 7 -; Autograph Document Signed 2 v. 24-26 cm. (Bound 21)
    v. 1, Nov. 9, 1855 – May 4, 1856
    v. 2, May 5, 1856 – Feb. 7, 1857.
  - Huntington County circuit court, U.S. naturalization of German emigrate, 1 Oct. 1856 (Box 2)
  - Terre Haute, Ind. Public schools. Lease for three months to two upper rooms of school house no. 2 in the city of Terre Haute by the School Trustees of the city of F. V. Birkowsky, secretary of the German English School Society., 1857, Apr. 1 -; Autograph Document Signed, 3 items, 1 p. 30 cm.; genreform: photostats. (Box 2)
    Accompanied by:
    [1] Lease for three months of the south room of School house no. 3 in the city of Terre Haute by the School trustees to L. B. Franklin, teacher, May 25, 1857.
    (Autograph Document Signed 1 p. 21 cm.)
    [2] Report of J. H. Moore, superintendent to the Trustees of the public schools of Terre Haute, Ind. for the five months ending March 1, 1861, (Document Signed 1 p. 24 cm.)
  - Prow, Christian, 1819-, merchant, state legislator, and William Collier, merchant. [Ledger for store at Campbellsburg, Ind]., 1857-1863 -; Autograph Document 424 pp. 37 cm.; bound. (Bound 22)
    1) letter for R. D. Porter per H. P. Fair to Messers Christian Prow and William Collier, Mar. 30, 1858, on letterhead of Office of the Oriental Life Liniment, Louisville, Ky. (Autograph Letter Signed 2 pp. 20.5 cm.)
    2) letter of Edward J. Salyards 1820- merchant of Orleans, Ind., to Christian Prow, Feb. 22, 1859, offering to sell "som [sic] marble." (Autograph Letter Signed 2 pp. 19 cm.)
    3) The Eastern Star point advertising card of Rob Morris and D. T. Monsarrat of Louisville, Ky., n.d. (Prow and Collier were members of Rob Morris Lodge No. 282 at Cambellsburg)
    4) Leaflet advertising Dr. Rogers' Liverwort, Tar, and Canchalagua, ca. 1858.
  - ca. Brier, William. Enrollment Records, 1857-1892 (Box 2)
    Manuscript book with 20 pages of records for the enrollment of 127 men for military duty, including several "colored," in Rainsville, Warren County, Indiana. Information recorded includes age, trade, place of birth, former military service, and details about service. The book also contains several pages of post-war farm workers' records, maps of farm plantings, music instruction, and a lecture on Lafayette.
    Printed letter, 1863, relating to the appointment of Brier as enrolling officer in Pine Township, Warren County, Indiana.
  - Smith, Oliver Hampton, 1794-1859, U.S. senator. Indianapolis, Indiana. To Editors, Home Journal. Thanks them for the favorable notice of his book and gives them permission to quote from his book., 1858, Feb. 23 -; Autograph Letter Signed 1 p. 21 cm. (Box 2)
    Removed from Smith's Early Indiana Trials … Cincinnati, Moore, Wilstach, Keys and Co., 1858. (Lilly F527.S656). 1973
  - Holmes, George Hamilton Moore, farmer. Livonia, Washington County, Indiana. Diaries., 1858, June 9-1873, Dec. 31 -; Autograph Document Signed, 3 items, 3 v. 16 cm. (Box 2)
    June 9, 1858 – June 30, 1859
    1864
    1872-1873.
    Only the first diary carries signature and place of residence of diarist.
  - Daybook of a general store, Aurora, Ind., 1858, July 1-1865, Apr. 5 -; Autograph Document 235 p. 30 cm. (Bound 23)
    Various names of members of Beinkamp and Rothert families appear on front and back end papers and front fly leaf.
  - Bainbridge Male and Female Academy, Bainbridge, Ind. Minutes., 1859, Feb. 14-1860, Jan. 28 -; Autograph Document 184 p. 25 cm. (Bound 24)
  - Chicago, Indianapolis, and Louisville railway company. Certificate of stock of the Louisville, New Albany and Chicago RailRoad Co., dated December 17, 1859, and issued to John Vestal., 1859, Dec. 17 -; Document Signed 1 p.; 13 x 25 cm. (Box 2)
    Signed by D. A. Noble, president and George Lyman, secretary. Accompanied by: New Albany and Salem Railroad time table no. 12 to take effect Monday, April 7, 1856. Printed broadsheet.
  - Magann, Edwin W., fl. 1897, physician. Ledger, listing charges for medical services, Sept. 12, 1860-Sept. 28, 1866 and Jan. 6, 1891-May 27, 1897., 1860, Sept. 12-1897, May 27 -; Autograph Document [20 p.], p. 1-120, 122, 124-222, [1 p.] (Bound 25)
    No pages lacking. Pages 121 and 123 omitted in numbering.
  - Mayfield, Leroy Sam., 1841-, Civil War soldier. Letters and diaries., 1860, Oct. 7-1864, June 30 -; Typed copy of Autograph Letter Signed & Autograph Document Signed 125 p. 28 cm. (Box 2)
    1) Mayfield, Leroy Sam. 34 letters to his brother Joseph M. Mayfield, Oct. 7, 1860-Dec. 1863; 66 p.
    2) Diary, Book I, Aug. 17-Dec. 13, 1863. 33 p.
    3) Diary, book II, Mar. 23-June 30, 1864. 26 p.
    Printed with omissions as: "A Hoosier invades the Confederacy: Letters and diaries of Leroy S. Mayfield, contributed by Ura Sanders, ed. John D. Barnhart. Indiana Magazine of History, 39: 144-91, June 1943.
    Transcribed from the originals in the possession of Ura Sanders, Gosport, Indiana. 1951
  - Magann, Edwin W., M.D. Daybook, listing charges for medical service, Apr. 6, 1861-Jan. 3, 1864; Sept. 11, 1865-Sept. 24, 1866; Jan. 6, 1891-Feb. 23, 1896., 1861, Apr. 6-1896, Feb. 23 -; Autograph Document 100 p. 35 cm. (Box 2)
    Bills and receipts are in a pocket on the inside back cover of the volume:
    1) Jenkins & Hatch, importers, Cincinnati, Ohio, Jan. 10, 1863. Receipted bill to E. W. Magann. (Autograph Document Signed 1 p. 13 cm.)
    2) Potts, E. G. Richmond, Feb. 3, 1863. Receipted bill to Dr. Magan. (Autograph Document Signed 1 p. 9 cm.)
    3) Magann, E. W. Tickfaw, Louisiana, Oct. 11, 1892, Bill to Mrs. M. F. Pucket. (Autograph Document Signed 1 p. 10 cm.)
    Pages containing accounts of Apr. 6, 1861-Sept. 24, 1866 are headed: Hagerstown, Indiana.
  - Fletcher, William Baldwin, 1837-1907, physician. [Civil War Journal.], 1861, Apr. 13-June 27 -; Autograph Document 54 p. 20 cm. (Bound 26)
    Illustrated with pen and ink sketches.
    Published as "The Civil War Journal of William B. Fletcher." contributed and edited by Loriman S. Brigham, Indiana Magazine of History, LVII: [43]-76, March 1961.
  - Morton, Oliver Perry, 1823-1877, governor of Indiana. Indianapolis, Indiana. To Abraham Lincoln. Requests the appointment of Joseph J. Reynolds as a brigadier general., 1861, June 9 -; Autograph Letter Signed 1 p. 25 cm. (Box 2)
    On verso of letter is an eight-line endorsement by Lincoln to the secretary of war, June 12, 1861.
  - Lincoln, Abraham, 1809-1865, pres. U.S. To Simon Cameron. Endorses appointment of Joseph J. Reynolds as a brigadier general., 1861, June 12 -; Autograph Note Signed 25 cm. (Box 2)
    On verso of letter from Perry to Lincoln, June 9, 1861.
  - Dillman, Henry Franklin, 1838-1917, farmer. Civil War diary., 1861, Aug. 26-1864, Jan. 5 -; Autograph Document Signed [92] p.; 8 x 12 cm. (Box 2)
    Published in the Daily Herald-Telephone, Bloomington, Indiana, January 23, 1961.
    Gift. 1972.
  - Indiana Infantry. 34th regt., 1861-1866. Co. G, Payroll. Major John A. Lowry, paymaster., 1861, Sept. 21-Oct. 31 -; Document Signed 2 p.; folio.; 45 x 58 cm. (Box 5)
  - Indiana infantry. 57th regt., 1861-1865. Orderly book., 1861, Dec. 16-1863, Mar. 20 -; Autograph Document [72] p. (Bound 27)
    Lower corners torn from pp. 69-72.
    Purchase. 1956
  - Carson, R. B., agent,; Farmers' and Merchants' Insurance co., Indianapolis, Indiana. Printed card giving capital, officers, directors, and references signed by R. B. Carson., 1861 -; Document Signed 2 p. 7 cm. (Box 2)
  - Indiana infantry. 57th regt., 1861-1865., Autograph Document [46] + 173 p. 40 cm. (Bound 28)
    1) lists of commissioned and non-commisssioned officers with dates of appointment and discharge
    2) lists of the enlisted men of each company, giving for each man his age, physical description, birthplace, occupation, place and date of enlistment and date and circumstances of discharge.
  - Indiana infantry. 36th regt., Co. H. Muster-out roll of captain Gilbert Trusler, capt. commanding the company, and William Grose, col., mustering officer, 36th regiment of Indiana volunteers, called into servicde on 28 Aug. 1861 to serve for three years from the date of enrollment, from 31 Oct. 1861 to 28 Feb. 1862., 1861 Oct. 31; Document Signed 2 p.; folio.; 54 x 78 cm. (Box 5)
    Signed by Gilbert Trusler, capt. commanding the company, and William Grose, col., mustering officer.
  - Fletcher, Stephen Keyes, 1840-1897, businessman. Civil War Diary., 1862, Mar. 3-Oct. 12 -; Autograph Document Signed 93 p. 21 cm. (Bound 29)
    Illustrated with pen and pencil drawings.